{
    "id": "ae668aeaa551474194c02d7e27747877",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I was taken ............................. when they told me that I had failed.",
            "description": "To be taken aback is to be shocked.",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "over",
                "aback"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "be5cd2a9b4394f05abcb053614a276dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She takes ............................ her mother.",
            "description": "To take after somebody is to resemble them.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "off",
                "after"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ff1367bb04a544e4a743cb82f540650c"
        },
        {
            "question": "My brother tried to take ............................... my toys but I didn't let him.",
            "description": "To take something away is to remove it from somebody.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "away",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c4ad9e856f074024b1dfec01675eb68c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The minister refused to take ………………….. his remarks.",
            "description": "To take your remarks back is to retract them.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "back",
                "down"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "48cc1a942d6a49ada425d4876314c485"
        },
        {
            "question": "The court ordered the company to take ………………………. their hoardings.",
            "description": "To take something down is to remove it. ",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "in",
                "down"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "df6aaccb14b14aa3b08cd83ef6c8e2be"
        },
        {
            "question": "I took him ………………………. a foreigner.",
            "description": "Take for means regard as.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "for",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2002ea724f514a0aa1b8330a82f86ecd"
        },
        {
            "question": "A kind woman took …………………….. the pup that was abandoned by its masters.",
            "description": "To take someone in is to give home to them.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "out",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "de99f2bbcd0a4b7cba456292c1acfa9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Please take ……………………….. your shoes before entering the temple.",
            "description": "To take off shoes is to remove them.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "off",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "70e97b489660450286e2ba86950ceb74"
        },
        {
            "question": "The plane took ……………………… at the scheduled time.",
            "description": "When a plane takes off, it begins to fly.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "off",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5724147f42874dddaef97b8d114192de"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want to take …………………….. any more work at the moment.",
            "description": "To take on work is to agree to do it.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on",
                "out"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0febe68bb411499195137c7e23a58d73"
        },
        {
            "question": "The company is planning to take …………………………… more programmers.",
            "description": "To take on people is to hire them. ",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1f7c130f4ca44617b40f2501426b52cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "A multinational firm is going to take ………………………… our company.",
            "description": "To take over a company is to gain control of it.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "off",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "827fd6f70fc348418c1cb87ba58663ff"
        }
    ]
}